Eugene Van Cleef Papers 1906-1973 Mss.Ms.Coll.61
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 3 lin. feet
  - Subseries A. Correspondence, 1909-1973; 36 folders
    - Laine, Oliver H., 1940 (Box 4)
      See also: Beaton, W. S.; Hill, Karl E.; Kaye, V. J.; Kolehmainen, John I.
    - Lancaster, Jane, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Lantis, David W., 1950-1969 (Box 4)
    - Larson, Ruth J., 1937 (Box 4)
    - Lausche, Frank J., 1964-1967 (Box 4)
    - Lautzenheiser, John A., 1963 (Box 4)
    - Lazarus, Charles Y., 1964-1968 (Box 4)
    - Legation of Finland, 1930-1941 (Box 4)
    - Lehtinen, A., 1945-1951 (Box 4)
    - Lemmon, Howard F., 1964 (Box 4)
    - Levy, Robert K. S. R., 1965-1966 (Box 4)
      Dolsti, C.; Jarnefelt. See also: Procopé, Hjalmar; Seppälä, Richard R.; Sihvola, Jorma; Solanico, Risto; Tuominen, Leo; Von Numers, Sigurd
    - Levy, Ruth, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Lezius, Walter G., 1937 (Box 4)
      Port of New York Authority
    - Lieser, David, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Lojacono, Salvatore, 1935 (Box 4)
      Pergamon Press. See also: Dunagan, Michael W.; United Feature Syndicate
    - Long, Clyde C., 1965 (Box 4)
    - Long, Edward H., 1965 (Box 4)
      Columbus Area Chamber of Commerce. See also: Everson, Carl M.; Knepper, William E.; Martin, Rosemary; Rieley, Gordon; Roberts, Kline L.; Starkey, Delmar G.; Black, Elaine; Sweeney, Robert E.
    - Los Angeles, City of, 1970 (Box 4)
      Morgan Heights Sanatorium
    - Ludwin, Leonard, 1945 (Box 4)
      Columbus Dispatch
    - Luoma, Jack, 1950-1951 (Box 4)
    - Luxon, Norval Neil, 1948-1953 (Box 4)
      Ames, Rockwell; Hamilton, Calvin S.; Falick, Abraham J.; Office of Voluntary Housing Development
    - McBryde, F. W., 1943 (Box 4)
    - McClintock, Mike M., 1970 (Box 4)
    - McClintock, Richard H., 1949 (Box 4)
    - McClure, Peter, 1946 (Box 4)
    - McClure, Russell S., 1942-1950 (Box 4)
    - McCoy, Edwin L., 1952 (Box 4)
      See also: Greer, Howard C.
    - McCoy, James R., 1966 (Box 4)
    - McDonough, Douglas, 1967-1968 (Box 4)
    - McDonald, J. W., 1948 (Box 4)
    - MacFarlane, Eileen W. E., 1942 (Box 4)
    - McGowan, J. S., 1950 (Box 4)
      Journal of Property Management
    - McMillan, James D., 1967 (Box 4)
    - McWhorter, Paul, 1950 (Box 4)
    - Malone, Thomas F., 1953-1954 (Box 4)
    - Margolis, Lorna G., 1968 (Box 4)
    - Markus, E., 1948 (Box 4)
    - Marrone, Joseph M., 1959 (Box 4)
    - Martin, Geoffrey J., 1969-1973 (Box 4)
      Library of Congress Copyright Office. See also: Register of Copyrights
    - Martin, Rosemary, 1953-1966 (Box 4)
    - Mather, Cotton, 1964 (Box 4)
      U. S. Department of Commerce. See also: U. S. Department of Commerce; Corzine, Harold A.; Burgess, George K.; Kalstrom, G. W.; Roberts, F. L.; Roterus, Victor; Schnellbacher, E. E.; Bendler, L. J.
    - Mather, Whitly F., 1937 (Box 4)
    - Maxfield, Orland, 1954 (Box 4)
      Columbus Area Chamber of Commerce. See also: Everson, Carl M.; Knepper, William E.; Lieser, David; Rieley, Gordon; Roberts, Kline L.; Starkey, Delmar G.; Black, Elaine; Sweeney, Robert E.
    - Mayer, Harold M., 1969-1972 (Box 4)
    - Mayerhoff, Howard A., 1953-1955 (Box 4)
    - Mead, W., 1953 (Box 4)
    - Mee, John F., 1971 (Box 4)
    - Merriam, G. & C Company, 1939-1941 (Box 4)
    - Metcalf, H. D., 1953 (Box 4)
    - Namias, Jerome, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Nash, Peter H., 1965-1966 (Box 4)
    - National Council for Geographic Education, 1962-1973 (Box 4)
      Columbus (Ohio) Department of Public Service. See also: Crozier, James R.; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Portman, M. D.; Rhodes, James A.; Sensenbrenner, M. E.; Armstrong, Warren; Gregg, Albert B; Westlake, W.
    - Nelson, Donald S., 1968-1970 (Box 4)
    - Nelson, John, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Nelson, Norman, 1970 (Box 4)
      Ball, John M.; Ekblaw, Sidney E.; Anderzhon, Mamie L.; Carls, Norman; Houk, Richard J.; Bacon, Philip
    - Noble, Allen G., 1967 (Box 4)
    - Northart, Leo J., 1964 (Box 4)
    - Notestine, Homer D., 1956 (Box 4)
      Field Museum of Natural History
    - Nott, Lois M., 1961 (Box 4)
    - Nystrom, Warren, 1965 (Box 4)
    - A. J. Nystrom and Co., 1959 (Box 4)
    - O'Brien, James, 1968 (Box 4)
      City of Upper Arlington. See also: Glander, Charles F.; Traphagan, Charles R.; Wells, R. C.
    - Ochi, Norio, 1968 (Box 4)
      See also: Association of American Geographers; Raup, H. F.; Borchert, John R.; Clark, Andrew H.; Spenser, J. E.; James, Preston
    - Oestreicher, Robert T., 1953 (Box 4)
      Daehn, Robert E.
    - Ohio Academy of Science, 1932-1963 (Box 4)
    - Student Correspondence, 1942-1957 (Box 4)
      Japan Trade Center
    - Oinonen, Lillian, 1964 (Box 4)
      Columbus (Ohio). See also: Crozier, James; Metcalf, H. D.; Portman, M. d.; Rhodes, James A.; Sensenbrenner, M. E.; Armstrong, Warren; Gregg, Albert B.; Westlake, W. Ralston; Simon, Frederick J.
    - Oliver, A. Russell, 1937 (Box 4)
    - Palkot, Edward J., 1964 (Box 5)
    - Palmer, Edgar Z., 1958-1959 (Box 5)
      Ohio Finnish American Historical Society
    - Paloheimo, Y. A., 1940 (Box 5)
    - Papier, William, 1964 (Box 5)
    - Parker, Edith P., n. d. (Box 5)
    - Partsch, Joseph, 1913-1923 (Box 5)
      See also: Finlandia Foundation
    - Passarge, Siegfried, 1938 (Box 5)
      Ohio Bureau of Unemployment Compensation
    - Patterson, Henry C. (Mrs. ), 1971 (Box 5)
    - Patton, Donald J., 1972 (Box 5)
    - Peacock, F. Edward, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Pehkonen, R., 1950 (Box 5)
      Chester (Pa. ) See also: Keekala, John M.; Holmes, Leo S.; Jalkamen, Ralph J.
    - Perry, Armstrong, 1934 (Box 5)
    - Peters, Adele C., 1936-1937 (Box 5)
      Rand McNally and Co.
    - Penck, Albrecht, 1928-1938 (Box 5)
    - Phillips, A. V., 1944 (Box 5)
    - Pico, Rafael, 1966-1968 (Box 5)
    - Pikarsky, Milton, 1967 (Box 5)
    - PLAN, Canada, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Pollak, Charles A., 1972 (Box 5)
    - Pool, K. E., 1952-1953 (Box 5)
      Chicago (Ill. ); Bureau of Engineering
    - Poole, S. P., 1943 (Box 5)
      Comay, Eli; Gertler, L. O.
    - Portman, M. D., 1966-1972 (Box 5)
    - Procopé, Hjalmar, 1940-1942 (Box 5)
    - Prevost, Antoine, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Pruitt, Evelyn L., 1962 (Box 5)
      Columbus (Ohio). See also: Metcalf, H. D.; Crozier, James R.; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Rhodes, James A.; Armstrong, Warren; Gregg, Albert b.; Westlake, W. Ralston; Simon, Frederick J.
    - Ragatz, Lowell, 1949 (Box 5)
      See also: Legation of Finland, Sihuola, Jorma; Sepälä, Hjalmar; Solanico, Risto; Tuominen, Leo; Von Numers, Sigurd
    - Rascher, A. C., 1955 (Box 5)
    - Raup, H. F., 1961-1972 (Box 5)
      United States Department of the Navy Office of Naval Research. See also: Bailey, Walter H.; Espenshade, Edward B. Jr.
    - Rautanen, V., 1940 (Box 5)
    - Redman, Albert E., 1957 (Box 5)
    - Reisman, Leonard E., 1964 (Box 5)
      See also: Association of American Geographers; Nystrom, Warren J.; Brochert, John R.; Claric, Andrew H.; James, Preston E.; Spenser, J. F.
    - Library of Congress. Copyright Office, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Reoston, Jeanne, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Rhodes, James A., 1949-1970 (Box 5)
    - Richardson, Edward A., 1959 (Box 5)
      See also: Marcolis, Lorna G.
    - Richardson, N. H., 1966 (Box 5)
    - Rieley, Gordon, 1954-1956 (Box 5)
      Columbus (Ohio). See also: Metcalf, H. D.; Crozier, James C.; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Portman, M. D.; Sensenbrenner, M. E.; Armstrong, Warren; Gregg, Albert B; Westlake, W. Ralston; Simon, Frederick J.
    - Rightmire, George W., 1928-1931 (Box 5)
    - Riley, J. Ralph, 1973 (Box 5)
      Town Planning Institute of Canada
    - Riley, James R., 1949-1970 (Box 5)
      See also: Everson, Carl M.; Lieser, David; Martin, Rosemary; Knepper, William E.; Roberts, Kline L.; Starkey, Delmar G.; Black, Elaine; Sweeney, Robert e.
    - Rizkalla, Zaki Shenata, 1966 (Box 5)
    - Roberts, F. L., 1946 (Box 5)
    - Roberts, Kline L., 1954-1968 (Box 5)
    - Ross, J. P., 1970 (Box 5)
    - Roterus, Victor, 1952 (Box 5)
      United States Department of Commerce. See also: Burgess, George K.; Corzine, Harold A.; Kalstrom, G. W.; roterus, Victor; Schnellbacher, E. E.; United States Department of Commerce; Bendler, L. J.; Marrone, Joseph M.
    - Ruggles, C. O., 1927 (Box 5)
      See also: Eerson, Carl M.; Knepper, David; Martin, Rosemary; Rieley, Gordon; Lieser, David; Starkey, Delmar; Black, Elaine; Sweeney, Robert E.
    - Russell, Joseph A., 1946 (Box 5)
    - Runte, E. L., 1959 (Box 5)
      United States Department of Commerce. See also: Burgess, George K.; Corzine, Harold A.; Kalstrom, G. W.; Roberts, F. L.; Schnellbacher, E. E.; United States Department of Commerce; Bendler, L. J.; Marrone, Joseph M.
    - Ryyanen, Elle M., 1968 (Box 5)
    - Saari, John, 1941 (Box 5)
    - Salomaa, V., 1950 (Box 5)
    - Salter, Christopher Lord, 1969-1970 (Box 5)
    - Saturday Evening Post, 1951-1969 (Box 5)
      Finnish-American Goodwill Committee
    - Sayre, Harrison, 1953 (Box 5)
      Timmins (Ont. )
    - Schmieder, Allen A., 1969 (Box 5)
    - Schneider, W. A., 1953 (Box 5)
      Fuos, Robert; Hibbs, Ben; Nelson, Frederic; Ratliff, Sherrie
    - Schnellbacher, E. E., 1946 (Box 5)
    - Schucman, Louis, 1949 (Box 5)
    - Schwemley, Glenn E., 1962 (Box 5)
      Franklin County (Ohio) Regional Planning Commission
    - Schwenker, Charles V., 1960 (Box 5)
      United States Department of Commerce. See also: Burgess, George K.; Corzine, Harold A.; Kalstrom, G. W.; Roberts, F. L.; Roerus, Victor; United States Department of Commerce; Bendler, L. J.; Marrone, Joseph M.
    - Sebeck, Thomas A., 1945 (Box 5)
    - Selby, M. E., 1966 (Box 5)
    - Semple, Ellen Churchill, 1929 (Box 5)
    - Sengupta, P., 1961-1968 (Box 5)
    - Sensenbrenner, M. E., 1959-1970 (Box 5)
    - Seppälä, Richard R., 1964-1965 (Box 5)
    - Shaw, A. H. C., 1948 (Box 5)
    - Shaw, Earl, 1936 (Box 5)
      Columbus (Ohio). See also: Metcalf, H. D.; Columbus (Ohio) Department of Public Service; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Portman, M. D.; Crozier, James R.; Rhodes, James; Anderson, Warren; Gregg, Albert B.; Westlake, W. Ralston; Simon, Frederick J.
    - Shy, Charles, 1969 (Box 5)
      Embassy of Finland. See also: Lgation of Finland; Procopé, Hjalmar; Sihvola, Jorma; Solanko, Risto; Ruominen, Leo; Von Numers, Sigurd
    - Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society, 1932-1966 (Box 5)
      Cleveland (Ohio)
    - Sihvola, Jorma, 1940 (Box 5)
    - Simon, Freerick J., 1964 (Box 5)
    - Singh, V. R., 1961 (Box 5)
      Daniels, Farrington; Holme, Thomas; Neville, Harvey A.; Ellery, Edward
    - Smith, Guy-Harold, 1927-1950 (Box 5)
      Legation of Finland. See also: Legation of Finland; Procopé, Hjalmar; Seppälä, Richard R.; Solanko, Risto; Tuominen, Leo; Von Numers, Sigurd
    - Smith, Robert G., 1969 (Box 5)
      Columbus (Ohio). See also: Metcalf, H. D.; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Portman, M. D.; Crozier, James R.; Rhodes, James A.; Armstrong, Warren; Gregg, Albert B.; Westlake, W. Ralston
    - Solanko, Risto, 1941 (Box 5)
    - Sommers, Lawrence N., 1956 (Box 5)
    - Spangler, Kenneth, 1965 (Box 5)
    - Stangh, John N., 1941 (Box 5)
      Legation of Finland. See also: Legation of Finland; Procopé, Hjalmar; Seppälä, Richard R.; Sihvola, Jorma; Tuominen, Leo; Von Numers, Sigurd
    - Starkey, Delmar G., 1953-1956 (Box 5)
    - Steeb, Carl E., 1939 (Box 5)
    - Stevens, Loyd A., 1929 (Box 5)
    - Steward, Julian H., 1941 (Box 5)
      Columbus (Ohio) Chamber of Commercs. See: Everson, Carl M.; Knepper, William E.; Lieser, Daivd; Martin, Rosemary; Rieley, Gordon; Roberts, Kline L.; Black, Elaine; Sweeney, Robert E.
    - Stewart, Milroy N., 1973 (Box 5)
    - Stites, Samuel, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Stollman, Israel, 1967 (Box 5)
      Smithsonian Institution Bureau of Ethnology
    - Stoner, L. A., 1967 (Box 5)
    - Straus, Helen Sachs (Mrs. Nathan), 1944-1946 (Box 5)
    - Strong, Miriam, 1956 (Box 5)
      See also: American Society of Planning Officials
    - Sturgis, Lyman, 1929 (Box 5)
    - Suloway, Marshall, 1967 (Box 5)
    - Suomen Maantieteellinen Seura, 1937-1962 (Box 2)
    - Summers, Don F., 1937 (Box 5)
      Ohio Planning Conference. See: Briers, Evalena
    - Sweeney, Robert E., 1966 (Box 6)
    - Taafe, Edward J., 1967 (Box 6)
      Chicago (Ill. ) Bureau of Engineering
    - Thurston, William R., 1957-1958 (Box 6)
    - Tower, Walter S., 1918 (Box 6)
      Columbus (Ohio) Area Chamber of Commerce. See also: Black, Elaine; Everson, Carl M.; Knepper, William E.; Lieser, David; Martin, Rosemary; Rieley, Gordon; Roberts, Kline L.; Starkey, Delmar G.
    - Traphagen, Charles R., 1973 (Box 6)
    - Treadon, Norman, 1963 (Box 6)
      National Academy of Science
    - Trigger, Mary F., 1949 (Box 6)
      United States Shipping Board
    - Tuominen, Leo, 1973 (Box 6)
      Upper Arlington (Ohio). See also: Glander, Charles F.; Nott, Lois M.; Well, R. C.
    - Ullensvang, Gulla, 1942 (Box 6)
    - Unknown, 1914 (Box 6)
    - Unknown, 1929 (Box 6)
      See also: Seppälä, Richard; Embassy of Finland; Legation of Finland; Procopé, Hjalmar; Sihvola, Jorma; Solanico, Risto; Von Numers, Sigurd
    - Unknown, 1942 (Box 6)
    - Unknown, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Unknown, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Unknown, 1967 (Box 6)
    - Unknown, 1970 (Box 6)
    - Unknown, Ernie, 1970 (Box 6)
      University of Sheffield Department of Geography
    - Unknown, n. d. (Box 6)
    - United Feature Syndicate, 1953-1972 (Box 6)
    - United States. Dept. of Commerce., 1972 (Box 6)
    - United States. Dept. of State., 1941 (Box 6)
    - United States. War Manpower Commission., 1941 (Box 6)
      Freeman, James L.; Dunagen, Michael W.
    - University of North Carolina Press, 1956 (Box 6)
      Corzine, Harold A. See also: Burgess, George K.; Kalstrom, G. W.; Roberts, F. L.; Roterus, Victor; Schnellbacher, E. E.; Bendler, L. J.; Marrone, Joseph M.; Corzine, Harold A.
    - [Valecha], n. d. (Box 6)
      Culbertson, Paul T.
    - Vallinkoski, J., 1953 (Box 6)
    - Van Cleef, Felix, 1937 (Box 6)
      Clark, Anne L.; Trade Centers and Trade Routes
    - Van Cleef, Noah, 1937 (Box 6)
    - Van Valkenberg, Samuel, 1938 (Box 6)
    - Vastyan, Albert A., 1971 (Box 6)
    - Visher, Stephen (Mrs. ), 1967 (Box 6)
    - Visher, Stephen S., 1940, 1964-1966 (Box 6)
    - Von Numers, Sigurd, 1937 (Box 6)
    - Von Wendt, Georg, 1932 (Box 6)
    - Voppel, Konrad, 1947 (Box 6)
    - Vorys, John M., 1953 (Box 6)
      See also: Legation of Finland; Procopé, Hjalmar; Seppälä, Richard R.; Sihvola, Jorma; Solanko, Risto; Tuominen, Leo
    - [Vouras], n. d. (Box 6)
    - Waananen, Xlmari, 1936 (Box 6)
    - Walker, Harvey, 1930 (Box 6)
    - Wallach, Philip, 1950 (Box 6)
    - Ward, Henry B., 1917 (Box 6)
    - Ward, Robert DeC., 1914 (Box 6)
    - Wasson, Thomas E. (Mrs. ), 1970 (Box 6)
    - Weaver, John G., 1966 (Box 6)
    - Weidler, Walter, 1928-1957 (Box 6)
    - Wells, R. C., 1962-1963 (Box 6)
    - Westlake, W. Ralston, 1960 (Box 6)
    - Whitbeck, R. H., 1927 (Box 6)
    - White, Jack L., 1972 (Box 6)
      Upper Arlington (Ohio). See also: Glander, Charles F.; Nott, Lois M.; Traphagan, Charles R.
    - Williams, Frank E., 1927-1938 (Box 6)
      Columbus (Ohio). See also: Armstrong, Warren; Crozier, James R.; Metcalf, H. D.; Oestreicher, Robert T.; Portman, M. d.; Rhodes, James A.; Sensenbrenner, M. E.; Gregg, Albert B; Simon, Frederick J.
    - Whitaker, J. R., 1940 (Box 6)
    - Wolnott, M., 1952 (Box 6)
    - Wood, H. E., 1950 (Box 6)
    - Wright, Harry III, 1954-1966 (Box 6)
    - Wuorinen, John, 1938 (Box 6)
    - Wyckoff, C. G., 1965 (Box 6)
      Manitoba (Canada) Department of Agriculture and Immigration
    - Yocum, James, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Youmans, Robert L., 1963 (Box 6)
    - Young, Francis A., 1956-1957 (Box 6)
    - Zack, Marilyn G. (Mrs. Frank), n. d. (Box 6)
    - Zelinsky, Wilbur, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Zierer, Clifford M., 1950 (Box 6)
      Conference Board of Associated Research Councils
  - Subseries B. Correspondence: Economic relation between cities and their immediate environment, 1972-1973; 0.5 lin. feet
    - Chambers of Commerce Addressee List, n.d. (Box 7)
    - Anderson, Owen A., 1972 (Box 7)
      Springfield (Ill.)
    - Appel, Herbert, 1972 (Box 7)
      Wichita Falls (Tex.)
    - Bens, Charles K., 1972 (Box 7)
      Schenectady (N.Y.)
    - Berry, Herbert L., 1972 (Box 7)
      Buffalo (N.Y.)
    - Brownlee, Thomas M., 1972 (Box 7)
      Orlando (Fla.)
    - Candela, Jerry, 1972 (Box 7)
      Erie (Pa.)
    - Douglas, S.C., 1972 (Box 7)
      Joliet (Ill.)
    - Esshinger, K.W., 1972 (Box 7)
      Green Bay (Wisc.)
    - Ferguson, Fred E., 1972 (Box 7)
      Chattanooga (Tenn.)
    - Flint (Mich.), 1972 (Box 7)
      Flint (Mich.)
    - Garnstt, Thomas, 1972 (Box 7)
      Madison (Wisc.)
    - Gurssett, Jack, 1972 (Box 7)
      Abilene (Tex.)
    - Johnson, Herbert N., 1972 (Box 7)
      Peoria (Ill.)
    - Kansas City (Mo.), 1972 (Box 7)
      Kansas City (Mo.)
    - Kochendorfer, Aurther C., 1972 (Box 7)
      Toledo (Ohio)
    - Martin, Amos, 1972 (Box 7)
      St. Paul (Minn.)
    - Massey, Art, 1972 (Box 7)
      Memphis (Tenn.)
    - Meeker, Gene, 1972 (Box 7)
      Waterloo (Ia.)
    - Moon, John F., 1972 (Box 7)
      Minneapolis (Minn.)
    - Nukel, R.A., 1972 (Box 7)
      Pittsburgh (Pa.)
    - Patillo, Leonard, 1972 (Box 7)
      Houston (Tex.)
    - Philadelphia (Pa.), 1972 (Box 7)
      Philadelphia (Pa.)
    - Rayburn, John E., 1972 (Box 7)
      Youngstown (Ohio)
    - Rucker, J.P. (Jack), 1972 (Box 7)
      Evansville (Ind.)
    - Stanfacher, David C., 1972 (Box 7)
      Racine (Wisc.)
    - Silven, E.G., 1972 (Box 7)
      Grand Rapids (Mich.)
    - Stebbins, Roland, 1972 (Box 7)
      Rockford (Ill.)
    - Steiner, J., 1972 (Box 7)
      Detroit (Mich.)
    - Super, W. Reese, 1972 (Box 7)
      Allentown (Pa.)
    - Sutton, Bill R., 1972 (Box 7)
      Fort Worth (Tex.)
    - Tetto, Michael, 1972 (Box 7)
      Rochester (N.Y.)
    - Van Vahrenkamp, 1972 (Box 7)
      Austin (Tex.)
    - Wannall, Robert J., 1972 (Box 7)
      Tampa (Fla.)
    - Wesenborg, J.H., 1972 (Box 7)
      Des Moines (Iowa)
    - Yocum, James C., 1972-1973 (Box 7)
- Series II. Manuscripts, 0.5 lin. feet
  - Amber notes (Box 8)
  - Annexation v. strangulations: A critical problem facing our cities (Box 8)
  - The central city eyes suburbia (Box 8)
  - Cities depend upon their environment (Box 8)
  - Columbus skyline zooms upward (Box 8)
  - Comments by Eugene Van Cleef at a College of Commerce faculty meeting, November 1955 (Box 8)
  - The developer and city planning (Box 8)
  - The economic relation between cities and the immediate environment of each (Box 8)
  - The engineer and city planning (Box 8)
  - The forgotten central city (Box 8)
  - Geography and creative thinking (Box 8)
  - Geography orients the individual (Box 8)
  - German garrisons in Finland (Box 8)
  - J. Paul Goode [eulogy] (Box 8)
  - The impact of the St. Lawrence Seaway on land transportation in the Great Lakes Region (Box 8)
  - Letters to the editor (Box 8)
  - Maps (Box 8)
  - The mutuality of property management and city planning (Box 8)
  - The need for a scientific approach to city planning (Box 8)
  - The Open Court successor to the Junior Open Court (Box 8)
  - Our big cities are too big (Box 8)
  - Practice for real life (Box 8)
  - A Program for geography in Cleveland (Box 8)
  - Planning as a unifying factor in cities (Box 8)
  - A proposal for a trade exhibition in Peru-Brazil (Box 8)
  - The re-birth of an old science (Box 8)
  - Signs are for the home folks (Box 8)
  - Some observations relative to M. W. Davis (Box 8)
  - Some recollections of a would-be meteorologist (Box 8)
  - Some thoughts on city planning (Box 8)
  - They live in canyons (Box 8)
  - This mayor needed no machine: he simply did an efficient job (Box 8)
  - A traveler looks at the Mediterranean public markets (Box 8)
  - Urban confusion (Box 8)
  - Which way are you going? (Box 8)
  - Whiter city planning? (Box 8)
  - Will this year's harvest make Germany self-sufficient? (Box 8)
- Series III. Travel Notes and Diaries, 1906-1962; 0.5 lin. feet
  28 books, 8 packets and 3 folders containing information on the development of Eugene Van Cleef's career, his goals, personal ambitions, and beliefs, with self assessments of his progress. These also contain observations on foreign culture and economics and architecture, notations on topography, climate, and agriculture. Collectively, these provide not only a record of Eugene Van Cleef's career, but his cultural, moral, and religious attitudes.
  - Pocket diaries and memorandum books, 1906-1921; 1; 23 items, ca.2x3" (Box 9)
  - My trip abroad, 1907; 2; 1 vol., lea. Bound with sheath spine (Box 9)
    Account of a trip to Europe with his mother
  - A letter to my friends, 1907; 3; 1 vol., lea. bound, 8x10" (Box 9)
    Impressions of places visited, with some postcards, and three photographs.
  - Handmade book, 1913; 4; 1 vol., cardboard covers (Box 9)
    Diary of European travel and year of study at Leipzig. Includes views on culture, religion, politics, economics, patriotism, and academic life.
  - Log and diary of European travel, 1935; 5; 1 vol., red card-stock cover; Van Cleef, Frieda Miller? (Box 9)
    Muted commentary, but with reference to Hitler's views on Jews.
  - Log and diary of European trave, 1935; 6; 1 vol., red card-stock cover; Van Cleef, Frieda Miller? (Box 9)
  - Notes on travel and Finns (loose pages), 1931-1937; 7; 8 folders (Box 9)
    - European tour, 1935 (Box 9)
      Notes on physical, economic, commercial, political, and social matters in countries visited.
    - "1931" (Box 9)
      Log of 1931 trip.
    - "Finland", 1923 (Box 9)
      Travel notes with cultural, political, economic, and physiographic observations.
    - "1937" (Box 9)
      Travel notes on Poland, Bucharest, Romania, and Germany. Includes political observations about oppression of Jews and Catholics in Germany.
    - "The Finns", 1917? (Box 9)
      Profiles of Finnish immigrants to the U.S.
    - "Finns Ohio", n.d. (Box 9)
      Profiles of Finnish immigrants to Ohio.
    - "Miscellaneous pages", 1922-1925 (Box 9)
      Newspaper clippings on the emergence of Finland and Finnish ethnic and economic matters. Notes on the Baltic states; contacts and books; notes on Hamburg and Lubeck.
    - "1932" (Box 9)
      Profiles of Finnish immigrants to Cape Cod, business, population history, and other ethnic groups, cranberry and strawberry claims.
  - "My trip abroad, U.S. Line", ca.1924; 8; 1 vol. (Box 9)
    Brief notes on distances, locations, temperatures, purchases, etc.
  - Travel log: Lisbon, Spain, 1962; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Travel log: Tehran, Beirut, Damascus, Bethlehem, Israel, Jaffa, Haifa, Nazareth, 1962; 1 folder (Box 9)
- Series IV. Subject files, 0.1 lin. feet
  Miscellaneous clippings, reports, and programs.
  - City planning (Box 10)
  - Constitutions (Box 10)
  - Foreign trade (Box 10)
  - Geography: science, academic interests (Box 10)
  - Personalities and business (Box 10)
- Series V. Autobiographical and Biographical Materials, 1913-1985; 0.2 lin. feet
  - Autobiography, ca.1960s-1983 (Box 10)
    Includes typescript and printed copy of autobiography printed in History of Geography Newsletter 3, (1983), 13-20.
  - Bibliography, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Biography, 1913-1985 (Box 10)
    Includes S. Earl Brown, "Eugene Van Cleef, 1887-1973," Geographers Biobibliographical Studies 9 (1985), 137-143.
- Series VI. Publication reviews, 1929-1963; 0.2 lin. feet
  Arranged alphabetically title of the publication reviewed or advertised.
  - Cities in action, 1941 (Box 10)
  - Con't count on "General Mud", 1943 (Box 10)
  - Finland: The Republic Farthest North, 1929 (Box 10)
  - City of Tomorrow, 1943 (Box 10)
  - Geography for the Businessman, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Getting into Foreign Trade, 1946 (Box 10)
  - Global Geography, 1963? (Box 10)